Fairfield Families Collection Ms 37
Fairfield Museum and History Center
- Gilden, Joseph Papers, Box VIII-Folder N
  Joseph Gilden, born in Stamford, CT, was a practicing chiropodist in Fairfield. He was one of the founding members of the Fairfield Lion's Club. The fishing license he was issued in 1943 includes his photograph and finger print, a means of reducing possible spying in the early years of World War II.
  These items were donated by Joseph himself in May of 1996 (L96May40).
  - Fishing license, 1943
  - Selective service classification cards, 1946-1947
  - Lion's Club membership card, 1973
- Glover, Addie M. Papers, Box IX-Folder H; The letter contains news of family and friends. No direct connection can be made between Addie Glover and the Glovers of Fairfield.
  - Letter from Wilma of South Framingham, MA to Addie Glover of South Quincy, 1886
- Goodsell Family Papers, 1771-1806; Box I-Folder U; 9 items
  - Writ, Stephen Brundage vs. Samuel Goodsell, 1771
  - Writ, John Goodsell vs. Moses Dimon, 1772
  - Writ, Ezekiel Canfield vs. Lewis Goodsell, 1772
  - Writ, David Hubbell vs. John Hubbell, 1781
  - Writ, Lewis Goodsell vs. Daniel Squier, 1786
  - Writ, Lewis Goodsell vs. David Smith, 1786
  - Ebenezer Howes vs. David Goodsell, 1787
  - Indenture between Lewis Goodsell and Walter Buddington, 1786
  - Bill to Captain Goodsell from Simon Schumerhorn, 1806
- Gorham Family Papers, 1770-1818; Box I-Folder V; 16 items
  - Writ, Andrew Rowland vs. Lockwood Gorham, 1770
  - Writ, Thad Banks vs. Jabez Gorman, 1771
  - Writ, Joseph Gorman vs. Benjamin Wynkoop, 1771
  - Writ, Mary Hazard vs. Mary Hazard, 1772
  - Writ, Shubil Gorham vs. Samuel Ogden, 1773
  - Writ, Shuball Gorman vs. Daniel Bradley, 1776
  - Writ, Lockwood Gorham vs. Belah Alvord, 1776
  - Miriam Gorham probate papers, 1770, 1771
  - Unknown probate papers
  - Deed from David Couch to Martha Gorham, 1779
  - Deed from Increase Struges, et al. to Joseph Gorham II, 1818
- Gray Family Account Books, 1802-1888; Box VIII-Folder I and J; 2 folders
  Asahel was the son of Aaron Gray (1780-1856) of Greenfield Hill. Asahel's son was John S. Gray, a butcher of Greenfield.
  - Asahel Johnson Gray Shoemaker's account book, 1842-1888; Folder I
    Gift of Charles Gray, Fairfield, Conn. on September 20, 1995 (L95 Sep 43). Asahel was the donor’s great-grandfather.
  - John Silliman Gray Butcher's account book; also includes labor account possibly from Aaron Gray, 1865, 1802-1806; Folder J
    Gift of Charles Gray, Fairfield, Conn., on September 20, 1995 (L95 Sep 43). See also the meat cleaver, part of the same donation, in the museum collection.
- Gray Family Papers, 1771-1870; Box I-Folder W; 19 items
  - Papers, 1771-1880; Folder W
    - Writ, John Batterson vs. Elisha Gray, 1771
    - Genealogy papers, n.d.; 2 items
    - Writing sample by Charles Gray, 1868
    - Papers from account book belonging to the Grays, 1864-1868; 11 items
    - Photocopies of pictures of houses built by Charles, 1920
    - Letterhead: Howard Gray, dealer in antique building materials
    - List of houses built by Charles Gray
    - Farm and shoemaker's account with Sharp and Whitcomb (fabrics dealer), accounts in front of book, N.Y., 1831-1833
    - Receipted note to Amos Madden from Burton Gray, 1809
  - Account book of Henry Gray, 1865-1870 (Oversize Item A)
- Green Family Papers, 1810-1893; Box I-Folder X; 13 items
  The Green Cottage was located in Green's Farms, CT. It was established around 1880 and given to the Working Girl's Vacation Society.
  - Material re: Misses L. M. and M. R. Green's School in New York City, 3 items
  - Memoriam booklets to Lucy Merriam Green, 1810-1893; 2 items
  - Green Cottage brochure with pictures, 3 items
  - Newspaper clippings, 5 items
- Griffin, Betty Papers, Box VI-Folder D; 8 items
  - Religious materials from Bible belonging to Betty Griffin of James St. in Fairfield
    This was a gift of Miss Regina Kiely of Bridgeport, CT on 10 August 1982.
- Hall Family Papers, 1802-1904; Box VII-Folders J-L; 35 items
  These items come from accession number 92.Oct.9
  - Papers, Folder J
    - Writ, Daniel Hall vs. Stephen Sherwood re: sheep, 1802
    - Writ re: return of sheep to Daniel Hall, 1802
    - Writ, Ebenezer Mallett vs. Nathan Wheeler, 1803
    - Writ, George Burr vs. George Platt, et al.
    - Promissory note from Daniel and Turney Hall, 1812
  - Bills to Coan and Hall, 1880; Folder K
  - Papers, Folder L
    - Ormel Hall's bank book, 1922
    - Carthage High School exercise and letters from Carthage, 1906
    - Letters to Clarissa Hall and teaching certificate
    - Wedding invitations to Zalmon Hall, 1879, 1881; 2 items
    - Miscellaneous letters, n.d.; 2 items
- Havard, Aline Papers, Box VI-Folder F
  Aline Havard was a local author, crippled with arthritis since high school, who lived on the Old Post Road. She wrote many children's stories. She died in Towson, MD. Further information is available in the folder.
  See the collection for Aline Havard's book The Two Runaways (813.54 H383T)
  This material from accession number L91.Mar.26
  - Typescript with correction of manuscript The Mountain Family: A Story of the Old Northwest by Aline Havard, 1959
- Hawkins Family Papers, Box I-Folder Y; 3 items
  - Account book in account with Allen Nichols, Southport, 1859
  - Post card and bill to Mrs. Clarissa Hawkins, 2 items
- Henshaw Family Papers, 1825-1855; Box I-Folder Ya; 7 items
  - Deed from Samuel Kellogg to Linus and Samuel Henshaw, 1825
  - Deed from Samuel Henshaw to Gideon Morehouse, 1832
  - Deed from Elizabeth Henshaw to Charles W. Sherman and James C. Hawley, 1852; 2 items
  - Deed from Robert Spencer to Elizabeth Henshaw, 1852
  - Deed from Samuel Henshaw to Charles W. Sherman, et al., 1855
  - Land abstracts, 1787-1832
- Holbrook Family Papers, 1837; Box VI-Folder A
  - Account book of Jonathan D. and Daniel Holbrook
- Howell Family Papers, 1845-1869; Box I-Folder Z; 9 items
  - Deed from Ira Benedict to William A. Howell, 1845
  - Deed from William White to William A. Howell, 1846
  - Deed from Eli B. Nichols to William A. Howell, 1852
  - Deed from William W. Howell to Henry B. Howell, 1852
  - Deed from Asariah B. Nichols to William W. and Henry B. Howell, 1853
  - Deed from Henry B. Howell to William W. Howell, 1855
  - Deed from Henry B. Howell, et al. to William W. Howell, 1863
  - Mary W. Howell probate papers, 1869; 2 items
- Hubbard Family Papers, 1738-1741; Box I-Folder Za; 2 items
  - Deed from John Whitmore to Zackariah Hubbard (Milford, CT), 1738
  - Power of attorney to Zackariah Hubbard, Fairfield hatter from Thomas Edwards, New York City goldsmith, 1741
- Hubbell Family Papers, 1681-1892; Box II-Folder A; 17 items
  The Hubbell family lived in the Stratfield, Greenfield and Newfield sections of Fairfield.
  - Deed from Richard Hubbell to John Hubbell, 1681
  - Deed from John Smith to Nathan Hubbell and Joseph Bradley, Jr., 1749
  - Deed from Abel Hubbell to Daniel Hubbell, 1750
  - Writ, David Hubble vs. Thaddeus Jennings, 1773
  - Writ, John Hubble vs. Daniel Robertson, 1781
  - Writ, Israel Blackman and Thaddeus Hubbell vs. Ebenezer Dimon, 1809
  - Mable Hubble probate papers, 1840; 2 items
    Gift of Mrs. Frederick A. Petrie from Hubbell House on Greenfield Hill.
  - Power of attorney to Ezra Hawley from Ezra Hubbell, 1751
  - Notes and bills, 8 items
- Jackson Family Papers, 1760-1906; Box II-Folder B; 25 items
  These items were a gift of Mrs. Lila Seeley Osborne Hall.
  - Deed from John Jackson to John Jackson, Jr., 1760; 2 items
  - Deed from Peter Jackson to John Jackson, Jr., 1775; 2 items
  - Deed from Samuel Lucey to John Jackson, Jr., 1776
  - Deed from Samuel Stevens, et al. to John Jackson, 1791
  - Deed from Daniel and Rachel Roberts from John and Nathan Jackson, 1800
  - Deed from Naomi Jackson to Jemima Jackson, 1813
  - Deed from Jemima Jackson to Samuel Jackson, 1828, 1831; 3 items
  - Deed from Amos O. Jackson to Samuel Jackson, 1831
  - Deed from Aaron Sears to Samuel Jackson and Amos Hill, 1831
  - Deed from George Hill to Samuel Jackson, 1844
  - Jemima Jackson probate papers, 1841; 6 items
  - John Jackson probate papers, 1810-1822; 2 items
  - Elizabeth F. Jackson probate papers, 1906
  - Military papers re: exemption from Samuel Jackson, 1820; 2 items
  - Map of John Jackson's homestead, 1811 (Oversize Box)
- Jennings, George A. Papers, Box VIII-Folder G; 1 item
  - Wedding toast given by Jennings at the marriage of his son George to Ida., 1880
- Johnson Family Papers, 1760-1822; Box II-Folder C; 3 items
  James Johnson (1734-1810) was born in Stratford and was the minister in the parish of Weston.
  - Pamela and Abiah Johnson probate papers, 1822; 2 items
  - James Johnson's Yale diploma, 1760
- Judah, Moses Papers, Box II-Folder D; 1 item
  Appraisal inventory of the late Moses Judah with probate papers. For further detail see Box I, Folder G, Callender Family Papers.
  - Estate account book, 1831-1832
- Judson Family Papers, 1769-1815; Box II-Folder E; 31 items
  David Judson (1757-1841) was born in Stratford and graduated from Yale in 1778. He settled in Fairfield and married Esther Bulkley in 1783. He was a storekeeper, postmaster, trustee of The Academy and founder of the first public library.
  - Deed from Josiah Hawley to Abner Judson, 1769
  - Deed from Ebenezer Knapp to David Judson, 1784
  - Deed from Ephraim Curtiss to David Judson, 1789
  - Deed from Wright White to David Judson, 1790, 1792
  - Deed from Stephen Fowler to David Judson, 1790, 1792
  - Deed from Peter Jennings to David Judson, 1792
  - Deed from Nehemiah Phippeny to David Judson, 1793
  - Deed from Gershom Burr to David Judson, 1795
  - Deed from Jese Benedict to David Judson, 1798
  - Deed from Ezra Hubbill to David Judson, 1802
  - Deed from Herman Humphrey to David Judson, 1817
  - Letter from Francis Sayre to David Judson, 1806-1807; 3 items
  - Letter from Francis Sayre to Mrs. Judson, 1807
  - Receipt from David Judson, 1813
  - Notes owed from David Judson, 1796-1805
  - David Judson's Yale diploma, 1778
  - Papers from David Judson's account book and name index from book, 9 items
  - Hermen Humphrey sermon, 1818
  - David Judson's Store Account Book, 1794-1815 (Oversize Item B)
- Kent (Hazard) Family Papers, 1771-1781; Box II-Folder F
  John Hazard (1719-1771) of Fairfield married Mary Wakeman in 1752. Mary was remarried to Moss Kent of Fredericksburg, NY. John Hazard owned several houses in Fairfield and Southport and was believed to be a Tory.
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. David Sturges, 1773
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Josiah Couch, 1773
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. John Crossman, 1773
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. John Batterson, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. William Batterson, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Joshua Baker, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Joseph Gold, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Isaac Oysterbank, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Jeremiah Sturges, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Nathaniel Down, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Archibal Cammel, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. Amos Williams, 1774
  - Writ, Moses and Mary Kent vs. George Cable, 1775
  - Moss Kent vs. Moses Bradley, 1781
  - Writ, Mary Hazard vs. Luke Guyer, 1771
  - Writ, Mary Hazard vs. Peter Blackman, 1772
  - Writ, Mary Hazard vs. Lothrop Lewis, 1773
  - Writ, Mary Hazard vs. Thomas Whitlock, 1773
  - Writ, Mary Hazard vs. Daniel Meeker, 1773
- Kruzsylak, William George, 1915-1927; Box VII-Folder N
  William George Kruzsylak farmed on Oldfield Rd.
  - School diploma, 1915 (Oversize Manuscript Box)
  - Wedding certificate for Cecelia Marie Haba and William George Kruzsylak from St. Thomas Church, 1927
- Lacey, Charlotte Alvord Papers, 1904-1939; Box VIII-Folders D-F; 3 folders
  - Diary, 1909; Folder D
  - Papers written by Lacey, Folder E
    - Fairfield, Connecticut: Then and Now, 1639-1939, 6 pages
    - Important People in Early Fairfield, 1940; 6 pages
  - Menu painted for Congregational Church, Southport, 1904; Folder F
- Lewis Family Papers, 1755-1847; Box II-Folder G; 14 items
  - Sturgis Lewis (1731-1753) probate papers, 1755
  - Lothrop Lewis (1702-1773) probate papers, n.d.
  - Jonathan Lewis (1728-1792) probate papers, 1793, 1794; 3 items
  - Lothrop Lewis (1759-1817) probate papers, 1817, 1818; 3 items
  - Unknown probate papers, n.d.
  - Deed from Samuel Hodges to Ichabod Lewis, 1814
  - Deed from Andrew L. Lewis to Moses J. Taylor, 1840
  - Bill to Hannah Lewis, 1773
  - Bill to R. Lewis, 1847
- Lockwood Family Papers, Box II-Folder H; 1 item
  - Deed from John Lockwood to Simon Couch, 1721
- Lowrey Family Papers, 1866-1897; 2 folders, 14 items
  Charles Lowery married Sarah Jones (1828-1911) of Fairfield.
  These items were given by Mrs. Charles Kouns (Marion P.) in memory of her mother Mrs. John B. Putnam. The accession number is 1983.27.
  - Passports and Photographs, Box II-Folder I; 11 items
    - Charles Lowery passport, 1866, 1869, 1870; 3 items
    - Sarah J. Lowery passport, 1897
  - Photographs of Charles and Sarah Lowery, Samuel Rowland and William Jones, 8 items (Oversize Manuscript Box)
  - Miscellaneous, Box VII-Folder H
    - Charles Lowery Yale Alpha Delta Phi autograph book, 1848
    - Fairfield Historical Society membership certificate for Sarah J. Lowery, 1908
- Mallett Family Papers, 1825-1886; Box II-Folder J; 9 items
  This Mallett family was from Fairfield, Trumbull and Easton.
  - Daniel Mallett estate papers, 1832, 1833; 4 items
  - Estate papers of Lewis Mallett, 1825
  - Bills to Josiah Mallett, 1850, 1886; 3 items
  - Letter to Annette Mallett
- McGarry, Patrick Papers, Box II-Folder K
  - Account book of meat market located in Fairfield on Spring Street near Cemetery Avenue., 1901-1902
    This item was from accession number L1981.June.3.
- Merchant Family Papers, 1793; Box II-Folder L; 4 items
  Joel Merchant and Levi Osborn are believed to have been partners in the clothier business.
  - Writ, Joel Merchant (Redding) vs. Elnathan Bradley
  - Writ, Joel Merchant (Redding) vs. Ebenezer Jessup
  - Writ, Joel Merchant and Levi Osborn vs. Abigail Sturges
  - Writ, Joel Merchant and Levi Osborn vs. Jesse Bennitt
- Middlebrook Family Papers, 1781-1875; Box II-Folder O; 5 items
  The Middlebrooks were origianlly from Fairfield. Elijah Middlebrook (1785-1859) of Trumbull was a physician and publisher of Middlebrook's New England Almanac for 54 years.
  - Writ, Jonathan Middlebrook vs. Nehemiah Burr, 1781
  - Writ, Oliver Middlebrook vs. Sarah Odell, 1785
  - Writ, Samuel Middlebrook vs. Gershom Hubbell, 1787
  - Writ, Chas. S. Middlebrook vs. John Lobdell, 1875
  - Bill to Oliver Middlebrook, 1825
- Milbank Family Papers, 1887; Box III-Folder A; 2 items
  Architectural drawings of the Milbank house are stored in the map case.
  - Specifications for house for Mrs. J. M. Milbank, Greenfield Hill, CT
- Mills Family Papers, 1788-1796; Box III-Folder B; 3 items
  - Writ, Eli Mills vs. Benjamin Smith, 1788
  - Writ, David Burr vs. Daniel Mills, 1794
  - Promissory note from Benjamin and Jeramiah Mills to Mathia Williamson, Jr., 1796
- Morris, Annie M. Papers, Box V-Folder E; 1 items
  - Autograph book belonging to Annie M. Morris, Greenfield Hill, CT`, 1891-1898
- Naphey, John H. Papers, Box VIII-Folder X
  John Naphey of Bridgeport served in the Connecticut National Guard, 4th Section, Machine Gun Battery.
  - Enlistment certificate, 1899
  - Appointments, 1898, 1902
- Nash Family Papers, 1773-1827; Box III-Folder C; 3 items
  Thomas Nash (1767-1814) lived in Westport.
  - Writ, Thomas Nash vs. Samuel Odell, 1773
  - Writ, Thomas Nash and Stephen Wakeman vs. Thomas Couch, 1774
  - Promissory note from William A. Batterson and Lewis N. Nash, 1827
- Neale, Harold W. Papers, 1915-1968; Box IX-Folders J and K; 2 folders
  Robson Place in Fairfield was developed by Henry Robson about 1915. Harold Neale was the donor's grandfather, who purchased lot #22, now numbered 55.
  - Plot plans for Robson place; plot plans of cess pools on Neale property, 1915; Folder J
  - Deeds and mortgage records; sewer tax receipts, 1916-1968; Folder K
- Osgood, Dr. Samuel papers, 1862-1941; Box III-Folder D and Box VI-Folder E; 2 folders
  Dr. Samuel Osgood (1812-1880) was a Unitarian minister in several churches, living in Fairfield only in the summer. His daughter, Mabel Osgood Wright (1859-1934) was an author and naturalist. She lived in Fairfield and was a close friend of Annie B. Jennings.
  - Papers, Box III-Folder E; 31 items
    - Programs given by Dr. Osgood, 1862-1865; 2 items
    - Letters re: Centennial program of 1776 and 1779, 1876-1879; 12 items
    - Letter to J. H. Beach re: Mary Osgood, 1892
    - Postcard re: Dr. Osgood's New York church, 1941
    - Envelope to Rev. Samuel Osgood, D. D.
  - Books from the library of Dr. Samuel Osgood, Box VI-Folder E; 14 items
    These books were a gift of the Connecticut Audubon Society.
    - The Dutch at the North Pole and the Dutch in Maine, New York Historical Society, 1857
    - Commemoration of the Conquest of New Netherland, New York Historical Society, 1864
    - The Government of Sir Edmund Andros over New England, New York Historical Society, 1867
    - Memoir of the Centennial Celebration of Burgoyne's Surrender, 1878
    - The Great Conspiracy and England's Neutrality, Mr. Jay's Address, 1861
    - Speech of the Hon. Charles Sumner, 1863
    - The True Grandeur of Nations: Mr. Sumner's Oration, 1845
    - Romanticism in its Relations to Rome by Francis Wharton, 1871
    - Oration of the Landing of the Pilgrim Fathers at Plymouth, 1871
    - An Address by Edward Everett, 1861
    - Bryant Among his Countrymen by Samuel Osgood, 1879
    - Sermon at the Consecration of the Church of th Messiah, 1868
    - "New England Magazine", 1832
    - A Popular Description of St. Paul's Cathedral, n.d.
- Parrack (Parrock) Family Papers, 1726-1888; Box III-Folder E; 22 items
  The spelling of the last names in this collection varied and later changed to Parrott.
  The bulk of the items in this series are accession number L81.Dec.1.
  - Obligation to Jonathan Wacklee from William, Daniel, John and Nathan Bardsle and Hannah Parrick (with photocopy), reverse side estate items to Hannah, 1726-1727; 3 items
  - Mary Parrack probate papers (Weston), 1810, 1818; 2 items
  - Petition of Gershom Bradley to Uriah Parrack, 1833
  - Bill to Daniel Parrick, 1847
  - Account received from Mary Parrock (Greenfield), 1848
  - Deed from Zachariah Squier to Elnathan Parrock, 1747
  - Deed from Elijah Hubbel to Elnathan Parrick, 1749
  - Deed from William Hill to Mary Parrack, 1764
  - Deed from Merwin (?) to Uriah Parrack, 1820
  - Deed from John Edwards to Daniel Parrack, 1859
  - Deed from Daniel Parrack to Deborah D. Parrack, 1859
  - Deed from Milo Lee to Daniel Parrack, 1859
  - Deed from Henry and Sarah A. Wheeler to Daniel Parrack, 1860
  - Deed from Deborah D. Parrack to Daniel Parrack, 1862
  - Deed from Silliman and Priscilla B. Godfrey to Daniel Parrack, 1867
  - Deed from William O. Sanford to Daniel Parrack, 1871
  - Deed from Daniel P. Parrack to Horace Fanton, 1873
  - Deed from Daniel P. Parrack to Alba Williams, 1874
  - Deed from Daniel P. Parrack to Seth Hill, et al., 1888
- Penfield Family Papers, 1794-1828; Box III-Folder F; 9 items
  Peter Penfield (1702-1772) was an early Fairfield settler. His two sons James (1732-1794) and Samuel (1734-1811) were successful business men.
  - James Penfield probate papers, 1794; 2 items
  - James Penfield (son) probate papers, 1828
  - Promissory note from Levi Mallery to Mary Penfield, 1775
  - Deed from Thaddeus Penfield to James Penfield, 1795
  - Deed from Nathan A. Hayes to James Penfield, 1803
  - Deed from Ebenezer Burr, II to James Penfield, 1810
  - Letter with table of genealogy, 1869
  - Samuel Penfield's store account book with index, 1786-1789
- Pepper Family Papers, 1903-1906; Box III-Folder G; 17 items
  Ellis S. Pepper was appointed receiver of the Southport Natioanl Bank which had gone into bankruptcy. His letters were written from many locations including Southport, CT where he had a room at Mrs. Ellwood's house.
  - Letters from Ellis S. Pepper to "Deary", 1903-1906; 15 items
  - A letter to Mrs. Pepper from Carrie Garrison Chappell, n.d.
  - Broadside of National Society of United States Daughters of 1812.
- Pike Family Papers, 1852-1859; Box III-Folder H; 33 items
  Samuel Pike (1827-1890), son of Julius Pike, ran a general store in Southport, CT.
  - Deed from Thomas H. Wheeler to Samuel Pike for horse and sausage making material, 1863
  - Handbills, 2 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to Samuel Pike, 1854-1857; 16 items
  - Letters to Samuel Pike, 1852-1856; 13 items
  - Letters to Meeker & Pike, 1859
- Prentice, Winthrop Papers, Box VI-Folder C
  Item is from accession number L89.Apr.21.
  Winthrop Prentice's father was Rev. Dwight Nelson Prentice, a pastor at Greenfield Hill Congregational Church.
  - Diary belonging to Winthrop Prentice, 1902
- Raymond Family Papers, Box VI-Folder B
  - Account books of Alva Raymond, 1823-1829, 1832-1859, 1865-1872; 3 items
  - Raymond genealogy paper
  - David Raymond account book, 1766-1852 (Oversize Item C)
- Redfield Family Papers, 1801-1807; Box III-Folder I; 15 items
  James Redfield (1763-1831) and Seth Redfield (1771-1813) were brothers.
  - Seth Redfield probate papers, 1813; 3 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to Seth Redfield, 1803-1807; 7 items
  - Bills and bills receipted to James Redfield, 1804; 4 items
  - Promissory note to Sarah Bulkley from Seth Redfield, 1806
- Riley Family Papers, 1836-1880; Box III-Folder J
  Patrick Riley (1813-1892) was born in Ireland. He married Delia Smith (1817-1901) and was listed as a carpenter in the 1850 census.
  - Deed from William Bulkley to Delia Riley, 1836
  - Deed from Alba D. Wood to Patrick Riley, 1838
  - Deed from Charles Jennings to Patrick Riley, 1882
  - Release of mortgage on Fairfield property, 1880
  - Patrick Riley naturalization papers, 1840
- Robenson (Robertson) Family Papers, Box V-Folder D; 1 item
  This item is from accession number L88.Apr.10.
  - Eunice Robenson's Common Place book, 1821; Lines to Mary Elizabeth Morehouse, written in 1847. She was born in 1832 and died in 1849, the daughter of Eunice Robenson (1790-1854) and Gideon Morehouse.
- Rodgers, Richard and Dorothy Papers, 1958-1980; Box III-Folder K; 4 items
  Richard Rodgers and his wife Dorothy had a house in Fairfield for many years. He died in 1980 having written lyrics for Broadway shows since 1920.
  - A penciled musical score of "You are Too Beautiful" written by Rodgers and Hart with accompanying letters, 1958; 2 items
  - Letters from Dorothy Rodgers to the Fairfield Historical Society, 1963, 1980; 2 items
- Rogers Family Papers, 1786-1791; Box III-Folder L; 4 items
  There are no published dates for the Rogers in this collection. Doctor Rogers is believed to have been a surgeon in the Revolutionary War.
  - Writ, Jediah Rogers vs. Hyat Banks, 1786
  - Writ, David Rogers vs. William Wakeman, 1791
  - Bill to David Rogers, 1787
  - Doctor David Rogers account letter, 1789-1790
- Rowland, Joseph F. Papers, Box IX-Folder B; 1 item
  Joseph Rowland was married to Delia S. Riley (1845-1873) of Southport. Letter was found in collections.
  - Letter from W. B. Randolph in Key West, Fla., to J. F. Rowland [Weston, Ct.], November 10, 1867, 1867 November 10; The letter describes the death of Rowland’s brother-in-law, Lieutenant George Riley, while serving in the Navy.
- Rumsey Family Papers, 1771-1790; Box IV-Folder K; 7 items
  - Writ, Joseph Rumsey vs. Daniel Bradley, 1771
  - Writ, David Rumsey vs. Solomon Couch, 1773
  - Writ, Walter Carson vs. David Rumsey, 1774
  - Writ, David Rumsey vs. Dennie Chapman, 1774
  - Writ, David Rumsey vs. Thomas Hill, 1776